Andy Humes

humes.andrew@gmail.com 614-975-7115 Denver, CO

Certified Ophthalmic Assistant ID# 241676

Refraction (plus-cylinder)- phoropter and trial frame	Tonometry- applanation, iCare, TonoPen	Perimetry- static and kinetic, automated and Goldmann
Traine	Tollorell	Goldmaini
Pachymetry	Corneal Topography- Pentacam, Zeiss	Fluorescein Angiography (FA)- Optos
Fundus Photography and Autofluorescence (FAF)- Optos	Electrophysiology- ERG, VEP, EOG	Ocular Coherence Tomography (OCT)- retinal, anterior segment, corneal
Corneal crosslinking- epithelium-off and epithelium-on	Phlebotomy and Autologous Serum Tears (ASTs)	Endothelial Cell Counts
Lensometry- manual and auto	Specimen Collection and Lab Testing	Slit-lamp Imaging
Visual Acuity Assessment- Snellen and ETDRS; PAM, BAT, and Glare	Autorefraction, Pupillary Distance, and Vertex Distance	Pupillary, CVF, and EOM Assessment
History Taking	Patient Preparation- intravitreal injections (IVIs), minor procedures	Scribing
Electronic Medical Records (EMRs)- ModMed, NextGen, Nextech	E-Prescribing and Prior-Authorizations	Triage, Patient Concerns, and Clinical Tasking
Equipment Maintenance and Troubleshooting	Inventory Management and Ordering	Scheduling, Training, and Management of Clinical Staff
Clinical Research	Informed Consent (ICF) Process	Subject Recruitment and Screening
Clinical Research Protocol Assessments	Investigational Product (IP) Management	Electronic Data Capture (EDC) and Subject Randomization

Achievements

Chapter leader for the Foundation Fighting Blindness (Denver, January 2018 to present).

Extensive experience performing patient work-ups, scribing, triage, diagnostic testing, and clinical research.

Leadership and higher level clinical experience as an Assistant Clinical Manager and Lead Technician.

Initiated, installed, and developed an electrodiagnostic testing department.

Integrated low-vision services and genetic testing into previous practices.

Education and Publications

Master of Science – Biomedical Science. Colorado State University, December 2013.

Bachelor of Science – Cell and Molecular Biology. The Ohio State University, June 2008.

Bachelor of Arts – Anthropology. The Ohio State University, June 2008.

Stuart, A. (2018, May). Inherited Retinal Diseases: Redefining Patient Care. EyeNet, 22(5), 42-48.

Alexander, J., Humes, A., Adam, M., MD, & Joondeph, B., MD. (2018, October). A Simplified Technique for In-Office Tap and Injection for Endophthalmitis. Retina Today, 13(7), 24.

Employment History

Ophthalmic Technician and Assistant Clinical Manager – Colorado Eye Consultants, May 2019 – November 2021

Performed essential duties of an ophthalmic assistant, including patient work-ups, scribing, and diagnostic testing.

Assisted in minor clinical procedures including epithelium-off corneal collagen crosslinking.

Temporarily served as the Assistant Clinical Manager.

Managed daily clinic flow, clinical staff, and staff shortages.

Scheduled clinical staff for weekly operation.

Trained clinical staff on technical skills and company policies.

Maintained and troubleshot diagnostic equipment and software. Coordinated with IT when needed.

Acted as a point of contact for other departments. Acted as the safety coordinator for the practice.

Established low-vision services and ensured seamless integration with clinic flow.

Maintained drug inventory and ordered supplies.

Requistioned, cultured, tested (Gram stain), and managed laboratory results of tissue specimens.

Called patients to address their questions, coordinate medications, and triage concerns to the physicians.

Andy Humes

humes.andrew@gmail.com 614-975-7115 Denver, CO

Clinical Research Coordinator - Colorado Eye Consultants, May 2019 - November 2021

Assisted the daily operation and coordination of clincal trials on site.

Recruited potential trial subjects and assisted in follow-up communication.

Explained and obtained informed consent for trial subjects.

Performed research trial protocol assessments and randomized subjects accordingly.

Performed trial frame refraction. Assessed 40cm and 1m ETDRS visual acuity.

Managed EDC data and research binders. Updated regulatory binders.

Managed, received, and tracked investigational product.

Completed daily logs. Generated and managed standard operating procedures (SOPs).

Certified research department equipment and testing lanes. Certified as trial photographer.

Attended clinical trial training sessions and site monitoring meetings. Communicated with IRBs and sponsors.

Coordinated subject compensation and submitted invoices per CTAs.

Assisted in our investigator-initiated trial for epithelium-on corneal collagen crosslinking.

Ocular Genetics Coordinator - Colorado Retina Associates, September 2017 - January 2019

Established and developed services for the inherited retinal diseases clinic.

Built the electrodiagnostic eye laboratory, performed the tests, and optimized the process. Vast experience in electroretinograms.

Performed manual and automatic perimetry with manual Goldmann, Zeiss, and Octopus platforms.

Arranged low-vision services to perform exams for the practice, shadowed services for the blind.

Collected samples for genetic testing and developed relationships with certified genetic counselors.

Academic and research activities including paper writing, database management, and statistics.

Lead Ophthalmic Technician and Ophthalmic Assistant– Colorado Retina Associates, August 2014 – August 2017

Performed all duties of an ophthalmic assistant, including screening, scribing, and imaging.

Supervised clinical staff during regular clinic hours.

Scheduled start times of staff, delegated breaks during clinic.

Performed more difficult clinical tasks and managed inventory.

Maintained equipment used by clinic, maintained and performed electrodiagnostic testing.

Managed incoming triage concerns, consulted physicians, and scheduled follow-ups as needed.

Trained staff on clinical skills and company policies. Served as a point of contact for other departments.

Assisted in patient flow in the clinic, jumping in to help where needed.

Research Assistant – 2009 – 2014

SomaLogic, Inc. - Research Assistant I, DNA Sequencing

Mitomics, Inc. – Research Assistant I, DNA Sequencing

The United States Bureau of Reclamation - Research Assistant, PCR Specialist

The Ohio State University - Research Assistant, Biochemistry